<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <author email="clabu@itn.liu.se">Claes Buckwalter</author>
        <title>The Elk Framework</title>
    </properties>
    <meta name="keyword" content="The Elk Framework, Elk, JDF, Job Definition Format, JMF, Job Messaging Format, CIP4, Device, Device Framework, Controller, JDF Framework, Java"/>
    <body>
        <section name="News">
                <ul>
                    <li>2006-06-01 - A new release of the Elk reference JDF devices is available for download. The <em>ConventionalPrinting</em> device's simulation model has been greatly imporved by Marco Kornrumpf, Arvato Systems, as part of his thesis project. The <em>Approval</em> device contains minor changes.
                       Download:
                       <ul>
                           <li><a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/downloads/elk-20060601-bin.zip">Binary distribution</a> (contains deployable ConventionalPrinting and Approval devices)</li>
                           <li><a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/downloads/elk-20060601-src.zip">Source distribution</a></li>
                        </ul>
                        Read the updated <a href="quickstart.html">Quick Start Guide</a> to get started.<br />
                        (The 20060531 Elk release briefly posted here has been removed because it contained an old version of Xerces that prevented Elk from running under Java 1.4. Sorry for the inconvenience.)
                    </li>
                    <li>2006-05-22 - Claes Buckwalter held an Elk tutorial at the CIP4 technical interop in Tokyo. Here are <a href="docs/elk-tutorial-tokyo-interop-2006.pdf">the slides</a>.</li>
                    <li>2006-01-19 - A new release of the Elk ConventionalPrinting device is available for download. The new release is based on JDFLib-J 2.1.3 and contains various bug fixes. One new feature is CheckJDF-J validation and device capability testing of all received JDF. The feature is enabled in Elk's <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/elk/config?cmd=showConfig">web-based GUI</a>. Download the pre-built deployable <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20060119.war">web application</a> (rename it elk.war) or the <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20060119-src.zip">source distribution</a>. View the <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/README.txt">README file</a> to get started.</li>
                    <li>2006-01-18 - Elk's issue tracking system has moved to CIP4's server: <a href="http://www.cip4.org/jira/">http://www.cip4.org/jira/</a></li>
                    <li>2005-11-14 - Claes Buckwalter and Ola Stering present Elk-related papers at <a href="http://www.printingfuturedays.com">Printing Future Days</a> in Chemnitz, Germany.</li>
                    <li>2005-11-04 - Claes Buckwalter and Ola Stering of the Elk team will be attending the CIP4 technical interop in Strasbourg 6-12 November. On the 6th they will give a tutorial on Elk and Alces.</li>
                    <li>2005-09-15 - <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/elk/">Try the online demo of the Elk 1.0 beta 1 Approval device</a></li>
                    <li>
                        2005-09-15 - Elk 1.0 beta 1. The Elk Framework and reference implementation reaches 1.0 beta. Features include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Implementation of the JDF 1.2 Base ICS 1.0 level 3 Worker Interface (hot folders excluded)</li>
                            <li>Device capabilities checking</li>
                            <li>Two simulated process implementations: Approval and ConventionalPrinting</li>                            
                            <li>Web-based user interface for monitoring</li>
                        </ul> 
                        Download Elk 1.0 beta 1:
                        <ul>
                            <li><a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-1.0-beta-1-approval.war">Approval process implementation</a> - zero-configuration deployable J2EE web application (WAR)</li>
                            <li><a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-1.0-beta-1-convprint.war">ConventionalPrinting process implementation</a> - zero-configuration deployable J2EE web application (WAR)</li>
                            <li><a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-1.0-beta-1-src.zip">Source distribution</a></li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>2005-08-05 - The Elk Project now has an issue tracking system where you can report bugs and suggest new features: <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/jira/">http://elk.itn.liu.se/jira/</a></li>
                    <li>2005-07-20 - Brian Ray of <a href="http://www.printable.com">Printable Technologies Inc.</a> has joined the <a href="team-list.html#Members">Elk project team</a>.</li>
                    <li>2005-07-15 - A new build of the Elk reference implementation is available for download. [<a href="changes-report.html#elk-20050715">Changes</a>] [<a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20050715.war">Deployable WAR</a>] [<a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20050715-src.zip">Source</a>]</li>
                    <li>2005-07-15 - <strong>Alces</strong> is a tool for testing software that implements the <em>worker interface</em> (see <a href="http://www.cip4.org/document_archive/documents/ICS-Base-1.0.pdf">Base ICS 1.0, appendix A</a>). Alces is used by the Elk team for regression testing of the Elk reference implementation. Visit the Alces web site for more information: <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/alces">http://elk.itn.liu.se/alces</a></li>
                    <li>2005-05-08 - A new build of the Elk reference implementation is available for download. [<a href="changes-report.html#elk-20050623">Changes</a>] [<a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20050623.war">Deployable WAR</a>] [<a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/elk-20050623-src.zip">Source</a>]</li>
                    <li>2005-05-08 - A new build of the Elk reference implementation is available for download. [<a href="changes-report.html#elk-20050508">Changes</a>] [<a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions/">Download</a>]</li>
                    <li>2005-04-27 - Slides from the Elk tutorial held at CIP4's technical interop in Pittsburgh have been added. [<a href="docs/elk-tutorial-pittsburgh.pdf">Download</a>]</li>
                    <li>2005-04-21 - A introduction to the Elk Framework will be given at CIP4's <em>JDF Developers Tutorial</em> on Sunday, April 24th, 2005 at PIA/GATF's headquarters in Sewickley, PA, USA. <a href="http://www.cip4.org">More info...</a></li>
                    <li>2005-04-19 - Claes Buckwalter presented a paper named <em>A JDF-enabled Workflow Simulation Tool</em> at <a href="http://www.taga.com">TAGA 2005</a> in Toronto, Canada. The work presented in the paper is largely based on the Elk Framework.</li>
                    <li>2005-03-10 - Thesis student Ola Stering has joined the <a href="team-list.html#Members">project team</a>. Ola will be working on the Elk project for the next five months and help make Elk fully compliant with the <a href="http://www.cip4.org/document_archive/ics.php">Base ICS</a> and <a href="http://www.cip4.org/document_archive/ics.php">MIS ICS</a>, level 3.</li>
                    <li>2005-01-29 - The <a href="docs/elk-dev-tutorial.pdf">developers tutorial</a> has been updated to cover building with Ant.</li>
                    <li>2005-01-28 - A <a href="quickstart.html">Quick Start Guide</a> for getting started with Elk has been added.</li>
                    <li>2005-01-27 - From now on Elk's <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions">binary distribution</a> will be the Elk reference device web application.</li>
                    <li>2005-01-27 - From now on Elk's <a href="http://elk.itn.liu.se/maven/elk/distributions">source distribution</a> will be bundled with an <a href="http://ant.apache.org">Ant</a> build script. Ant is now the preferred tool for building Elk.</li>
                    <li>2005-01-26 - Slides from the <a href="docs/elk-slides.pdf">Elk tutorial</a> and <a href="docs/jmf-slides.pdf">JMF tutorial</a> at CIP4's technical interop in Heidelberg have been added.</li>
                </ul>
            <p>
            Information about the changes in each new Elk release can be found in the <a href="changes-report.html">changes report</a>.
                </p>
        </section>
        <section name="The Elk Framework">
            <p>The main goal of the Elk Framework project is to create an
                application framework that provides the services needed by a JDF
                <em>Device</em> or <em>Controller</em>. The framework is
                implemented in Java and is based on <a
                href="http://www.cip4.org">CIP4</a>'s open source JDF Java SDK
                    <a href="http://www.cip4.org/open_source/index.html">JDFLib-J</a>.</p>
            <p>A sub-goal of the project is to create a reference implementation
                of the Elk Framework. The hope is that the reference
                implementation will be able to serve as a test tool and a
                starting point for others wishing to implement a JDF enabled system.</p>
            <p>Don't hesitate to contact the <a hre="team-list.html">project
                team</a> if you have any questions or if you want to get
                invovled in the Elk Framework project.</p>
        </section>
        <section name="Disclaimer">
            <p> The Elk Framework is distributed under the <a
                    href="http://www.cip4.org/open_source/cip4_software_license.html">
                    CIP4 Software License</a>. </p>
            <p> THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY
                EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
                THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A
                PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
                INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION FOR THE INTEGRATION OF PROCESSES IN
                PREPRESS, PRESS AND POSTPRESS OR ITS CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR
                ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR
                CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
                PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA,
                OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY
                THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR
                TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT
                OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY
                OF SUCH DAMAGE. </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
